Again?!
What the hell is that sound?!
While stopped at the ruins
of Utgard Castle to take a brief break,
the Scouts were overwhelmed by a Titan assault,
vanquishing their hope of survival.
--Nanaba...
--No! No!
--And Gelgar...
Father, stop!
However, in that moment...
Christa.
This is nothing more than a hope of mine...
I want you... to live a life you're proud of.
Ymir! Wait!
...Ymir suddenly transformed into a Titan.
Keep it up, Ymir!
Want live...?
Grab me!
This looks bad.
Ymir is...
This can't...
I still haven't told you my real name!
And then the main force of the Scouts
rushed in to engage the enemy.
Die!
They successfully dismantled the Titan attack.
However,
upon the ruins of battle,
Eren and the others learn a surprising truth.
Ymir...
My real name...
...is Historia.
"Warrior"
Slowly!
Bring it up slowly!
Raise it carefully now!
How's Ymir? What sort of shape is she in?
Her right arm and leg were bitten off,
and her insides are beaten like scrambled eggs.
If she was normal, she'd be dead for sure.
If she was normal, huh?
Reiner! Grab on!
Right!
Please, believe me!
I'm telling the truth!
Ymir transformed into a Titan
to fight off the other Titans and save us!
She did so with no regard for her own life,
which proves her loyalty to us, her comrades!
It's true that her judgement
until now is unforgivable.
After all, she may know things useful
to humanity and yet she kept quiet about it!
I imagine she didn't say anything
in order to protect herself.
But... now she's a changed person!
Ymir is an ally of humanity!
I know Ymir better than anybody.
She's a much simpler person than she looks!
I see.
Obviously, I hope we can build
a trusting relationship with her.
Her judgement aside, the information
she holds is a treasure for humanity.
I hope we get along.
But you know...
...even if she is a simple person,
this world becomes more of a
confusing mess with every passing day.
You said... your real name was Historia Reiss?
Yes, that's right.
Reiss, as in that noble family?
Yes.
I see.
Nice to meet you, Historia.
Yeah...
How's Ymir?
She's still in a coma.
Her bleeding has stopped, and we think
steam is coming out of her wounds.
For now, take her back to Trost
so she can get some proper medical care.
She's in your hands.
Understood.
Now then...
Our original mission... was to seal this wall.
Damn, it hurts.
You all right, Reiner?
Not by a long shot.
A Titan nearly gnawed off my arm.
That was... pathetic.
I thought I was done for.
Even someone as strong as you
gets this way sometimes.
What are you talking about?
This is the second time for me!
Tell him, Armin.
Huh?
Remember the time I almost
got crushed in that Titan's hand?
Oh...
Back then...
That makes twice I've nearly died.
At this rate, I'll be dead before I know it.
I picked this path on my own,
but being a soldier is rough.
It's like a soldier's spirit
breaks down before their body.
Though, until we plug up this wall,
there's no time to waste whining about it.
Yeah.
You two have been driven
far enough away from your hometown.
I'm thinking... this is where
we gotta draw the line.
He's right, Reiner!
Our hometown! Let's return!
Isn't it about time to go back?
Compared to all the trouble we've
been through, what's left to do is nothing!
That's right.
We're so close, it's just
another few steps till the end.
Huh?
What are you guys talking about?
Thanks, Mikasa.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine, but... Reiner got his arm bit
and Ymir is as you can see.
Who would've thought Ymir was a Titan, too?
Does that--?
Sasha.
Is everyone clear?
We'll deal with Ymir later.
And Conny...
I'll arrange for a Scout squad
to investigate your village later.
For the time being, I want you to focus
on the mission to fix the wall.
Got it?
Got it!
Still... I expected this place
to be swarming with Titans.
Hannes?
It's the Garrison's advance squad.
They came to tell us where the hole is.
There's no hole anywhere!
Huh?
We spent all night looking for it...
...but at least between Trost and Krolva District,
there's nothing wrong with the wall.
What'd you say?
We bumped into soldiers from Krolva
and retraced our steps.
We haven't seen any Titans the whole way here.
But... we know for sure there's Titans
on this side of the wall.
Did you actually look?
Are you sure you're not drunk?
I didn't drink!
Wait, why are all of you here anyways?
If there's no hole in the wall, so be it.
For now, we're falling back to Trost District!
Whatever you do, don't let your guard down.
We're going back ahead of you.
There's nothing wrong with the wall?
What could this mean?
There's been nothing like this in five years.
Why is it all happening now?
This world is getting more and more out of hand.
Eren.
Have a minute?
We need to talk.
What about?
Five years ago, we demolished the wall
and began our attack on humanity.
Oh no... What if there's a Titan
that dug a hole underneath the wall?
The hole will be hard to find in that case.
I'm the Armored Titan
and he's the Colossal Titan.
Right now, we need to focus
on getting Ymir back safely.
Even with our horses,
we still have to worry about Titans.
Huh?
What are you talking about?
Why are you telling him, Reiner?
Our primary goal was to ensure
all of humanity was wiped out,
but now there's no need for that.
Uh...
Eren.
If you agree to come with us, we won't
have to destroy any more of the walls.
Understand?
Huh?
No, wait! I don't understand at all!
I'm saying... Why don't you just come with us?
They are easily transported and assembled and are built in
such a way to capacitate emergency and tactical deployment."
I know this is sudden, but we need to go now.
Right now? Where will you take me?
I can't say that yet.
But... Well, it's something like our hometown.
So? What will it be, Eren?
Uh...
It's not a bad deal, right?
You can easily avert this crisis.
I wonder about that...
Hey! We're leaving!
What the hell?
And here I thought I had
enough to think about yesterday...
"12 hours earlier"
Eren?
"Ehrmich District"
What is it, Section Commander?
Oh, well...
I was finally able to get my hands on
the background report for Annie Leonhart.
Annie's?
Yeah.
It's taken so long to get it because managing
these reports is such a mess right now.
According to this,
there were two others belonging to the 104th
Cadet Corps who came from the same area as her.
And those two are...
...Reiner Braun... and Bertholdt Hoover.
Thanks to the chaos five years ago, pretty much
all of their family records are spotty or missing.
However...
During the long-range scouting formation,
their unit was given false information.
They were among those purposely told
that Eren was in the right wing.
The Female Titan attacked from the right wing!
Huh? What does that mean?
That it's possible they passed on
that information to Annie...
Why? Why would they tell Annie?
Hey, hold on a minute, Armin.
You can't just--
I know that, Eren.
By itself, that's not enough to prove anything.
So just in case, I'd like to hear from you
how these three interacted during training.
Know anything?
I knew Reiner and Bertholdt
were from the same place, but...
...they didn't seem close to Annie.
I agree.
I don't recall ever seeing the pair
talking to Annie that much.
Well, Annie didn't talk much in the first place.
When we ate, Annie would always sit alone
and munch on food by herself.
Oh! I've got something!
I heard a rumor she liked sweets,
even though she looks so grouchy!
I... don't remember.
But...
As their comrade,
I'd find it hard to believe.
Set aside Bertholdt, who doesn't say much.
Reiner is like everyone's big brother,
and he's not devious enough to deceive all of us.
I agree.
Reiner gave everything he had
fighting the Female Titan with me.
He would have gotten crushed
in her hand if he hadn't--
What's wrong?
Reiner managed to escape, but...
...Annie suddenly changed her course...
...and ran in the direction of Eren.
I...
I did mention that Eren might be
at the rear of the center rank.
But Annie was too far away to hear...
Seriously?
Did Reiner seem overly interested
in Eren's location?
Then... Where the hell is Eren?
It can't be...
I only started talking about Eren's position...
...because Reiner was the one
who asked about it first.
Furthermore...
...when that happened, the Female
Titan was staring at her palm.
He might have written a message
with his blades in her hand.
Reiner could've...
What the hell? Why are you
saying things like this?
--You should--
--Eren!
No... Everyone, listen up!
Supposing that we find Reiner or Bertholdt,
act in such a way as to not reveal any suspicions.
Of course, do not make any mention
of Annie Leonhart either.
Regardless if they're Annie's accomplices or not,
we need to lead them
deep underground and confine them.
Does everyone understand?
Yes!
You're just tired, aren't you?
Right, Bertholdt?
You've been through so much,
it's making you crazy.
Y-Yeah.
Reiner's just really tired.
Besides, if you were really the Armored Titan
that wants to destroy humanity...
...why would you be asking me
this in the first place?
What did you think would happen?
That I'd nod and say "Sure, let's go"?
Oh, right.
That's right.
What the hell was I thinking?
Have I really gone crazy?
Come on, let's go.
I see...
That's it.
I've been here too long for my own good.
It's been three long years...
surrounded by nothing but idiots.
We were just kids... We didn't know anything.
If only I never knew that
there were people like this...
I...
...wouldn't have become...
...such a half-assed piece of shit!
It's too late now...
I don't know what's right anymore.
But the only choice for me now...
...is to face the consequences of my actions...
...and as a warrior...
...fulfill my duty to the bitter end!
Reiner!
Are we doing it?! Now?! Right here?!
Yeah.
We settle this... right here, right now!
Eren!
Run!
Bertholdt!
Eren! Get out of there!
Ymir!
Eren!
I'm going to return to the hometown we lost.
That's all I care about now.
Bertholdt...
Reiner...
You damn traitors!
The Colossal Titan...
...as well as the Armored Titan,
engage the Scouts in battle.
If their mission is to exterminate all of humanity,
there is no turning back for them now.
Reiner and the others devote
their lives to the mission...
...because they are warriors.
Next episode: "Close Combat."